Guide to the University of Pittsburgh Women's Studies Program Records, 1970-2005 UA.15.26
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh, Women's Studies Program Records
1970-2005
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh
UA.15.26
10 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
The Women's Studies program at the University of Pittsburgh began in 1972 after notable unrest regarding social situations in Pittsburgh and the nation. The program has evolved over the years to aim in educating students about the social issues they currently face. This collection documents the development and administration of the Women's Studies Program though departmental and curriculum records.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection documents the development and administration of the Women's Studies Program at the University of Pittsburgh. It contains information regarding the curriculum of the program, conferences and activism, and committees created by those within the program. Additionally, it contains news articles about the program, and information about the Women's Studies Collection of grassroots publications previously held at Hillman Library.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
History
The Women's Studies program was created at the University of Pittsburgh in 1972. Over time, the interdisciplinary program reached a point where students were able to earn a major, minor, or certificate in women's studies. In 2013 the Women's Studies Program proposed a name change to the Gender, Sexuality and Women's Studies Program, and in 2015 this name change was officially approved by the University.
Acquisition Information
Deposited in several accessions from the Women's Studies Program beginning in 1997.
Education -- Curricula; Women's studies -- United States; University of Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh
- Department Information, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series includes information about the creation and development of the Women's Studies Program. It includes reports, proposals and planning documents outlining the formation and changes that occurred within the program.
  - Prologue to Women's Studies Program, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Women's Studies Program Five Year Report, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Term Reports, 1972-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Budget Information, 1972-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Budget Information, 1985-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Academic Feminism: The History of Women Studies at the University of Pittsburgh", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Creation of Women's Studies Program, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Development of Women's Studies Program, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Development of Women's Studies Program (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Women's Studies Program History Scrapbook, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Program Brochures, 1973-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Survey of Women's Studies Graduates, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Women's Studies Program Directory, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Women's Studies Certificate Program, 1974-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Proposal to Develop Faculty and Curriculum and Status Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Proposal to Develop Faculty, Curriculum and Evaluation, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Research Development Fund, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - News in Brief, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Status Report and Recommendations, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Women's Studies Program Directory, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Accreditation Self-Study, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Planning Documents, 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Research and Development Committee Research Directory Questionaires, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Research Directory, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Women's Educational Equity Act Program Proposal, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Fundraising, 1981-1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Women's Studies Program Directory Entries, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Sponsored Project Proposals, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Program Notes, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Resources for Women Wanting Careers in Engineering and Computers, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Women's Studies Program Directory Entries, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Women's Studies Program Posters, 1982 (Map-case 3-5, Oversize 1)
  - Long Range Planning Policies, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "The Contemporary Pitt Undergraduate" Survey, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Creation of "Contemporary Pitt Undergraduate" Survey, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Results of "Contemporary Pitt Undergraduate" Survey, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Professional Correspondence, 1984-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Affermative Action and Academic Research, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Apple for the Teacher Award, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The History of Women at Pitt Exhibit, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Diversity and Affirmative Action, 1990-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Self Appraisal Report, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Women's Studies Program Brochure, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Women's Studies Program Directory, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Women's Studies Program Research Questionnaire, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Director Search, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Women's Studies Program Long Term Planning, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Women's Health, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Personnel in Pittsburgh Area, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Withdrawing and Non-Returning Student Survey, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Letter From Barbra Hafer, Pennsylvania Auditor General, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Women's Studies National Endowment for the Humanities Grant (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Toward the 21st Century (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Towards A Theory of Feminist Criticism (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Steering Committee, II.
  This series includes the meeting minutes and agenda of the Women's Studies Steering Committee dating from the creation of the program in 1972 and through 2000.
  - Women's Studies Program Open Hearing, September 15, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, Academic Year, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Publications, III.
  This series contains publications created by the Women's Studies Program. It includes the monthly newsletters, In The News, and Synthesis.
  - Monthly Newsletters, 1.
    This subseries includes the Monthly Newsletters published by the Women's Studies Program from 1981 to 1996, as well as samples of earlier announcements and newsletters pertaining to the program.
    - Newsletters and Announcements, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Women's Studies Program Monthly Newsletters, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Women's Studies Program Monthly Newsletters, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Women's Studies Program Monthly Newsletters, 1991-1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - In the News, 2.
    This subseries includes the publication from the Women's Studies Program called In the News from 1996 to 2005.
    - Women's Studies News, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Women's Studies News, 1999-2005 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Synthesis, 3.
    This subseries includes the paper publication from the Women's Studies Program called Synthesis. This publication reported on women's issues and this subseries includes volumes from 1973 to 1988.
    - Synthesis Volume 1, Dec 1973-Apr 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Synthesis Volume 2, Sep 1974-Sep 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Synthesis Volume 3, Oct 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Synthesis Volume 4, Sep 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Synthesis Volume 5, Sep 1977- Aug 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Synthesis Volume 6, Sep 1978- Aug 1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Synthesis Volume 7, Sep 1979- Aug 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Synthesis Volume 8, Sep 1980- Aug 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Synthesis Volume 9, Sep 1981- Aug 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Synthesis Volume 10, Sep 1982- Aug 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Synthesis Volume 11-12, Sep 1983- Aug 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Curriculum, IV.
  This series includes descriptions of the courses that have been offered through the women's studies program. It contains course listings, course proposals and course syllabi from the creation of the program to the 1990s.
  - Course Listings, 1.
    This subseries includes lists of all the courses that were offered through the Women's Studies Program from 1973 to 1997. They are arranged by academic year.
    - Statistics of Women Students, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Education Statistics, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Course Enrollments, 1973-1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Course Listings, Academic Year, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Course Listings, 1977-1991 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Course Correspondence and Proposals, 2.
    This subseries includes correspondence about classes that were being offered, as well as discussions on the creation of new classes and the expansion of the program. It also includes the formal proposals for classes that were offered as part of the program. These materials are arranged by department in which the course would be administered.
    - Anthropology, 1975-1988 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Business, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Biological Science, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Child Development (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Classics, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Communications (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Comparative Literature, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Current Problems, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - East Asia Studies (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Economics, 1977-1993 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Education, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Ethnic Studies, 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - English, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Fine Arts, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - French and Italian, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Freshman Seminars, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs, 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Health, Physical, Recreation Education, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - History, 1975-1984 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Law, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Library and Information Science, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Linguistics, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Music, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Philosophy, 1974-1983 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Polical Science, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Psychiatry, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Psychology, 1973-1983 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Religious Studies, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Slavic, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Social Work, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Sociology, 1976-1983 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Speech, 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Course Syllabi, 3.
    This subseries includes the course syllabi for classes that were offered through the Women's Studies Program. Many include versions of syllabi that have changed through the years, as well as creation of new syllabi for classes. These materials are arranged by department.
    - Course Syllabi Lists, 1973-1990 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Course Syllabi Administration of Justice, 1979-1992 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Course Syllabi Anthropology, 1975-1995 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Course Syllabi Biological Science, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Course Syllabi Black Studies, 1985-1996 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Course Syllabi Classics, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Course Syllabi Communications, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Course Syllabi Comparative Literature, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Course Syllabi Current Problems, 1979-1993 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Course Syllabi Economics, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Course Syllabi Education, 1984-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Course Syllabi English, 1973-1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Course Syllabi English, 1990-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Course Syllabi Fine Arts, 1974-1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Course Syllabi Freshman Seminar, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Course Syllabi GSPIA, 1989-1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Course Syllabi Health, Physical Recreation Education, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Course Syllabi History, 1974-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Course Syllabi HSADM, 1992-1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Course Syllabi Law, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Course Syllabi Linguistics, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Course Syllabi Music (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Course Syllabi Philosophy, 1974-1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Course Syllabi Political Science, 1985-1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Course Syllabi Psychology, 1974-1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Course Syllabi Psychology, 1984-1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Course Syllabi Religious Studies, 1988-1992 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Course Syllabi Russian, 1989-1995 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Course Syllabi Slavic, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Course Syllabi Social Work, 1980-1995 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Course Syllabi Sociology, 1978-1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Course Syllabi Women's Studies, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Events and Programs, V.
  This series includes information about events and programs that were hosted by the Women's Studies Program. It contains fliers and lists of annual programming, as well as information about specific lectures.
  - Women's Studies Program Receptions, 1977-1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Women's Studies List of Events, 1973-1985 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Celebrating 100 Years of Women Students, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cornaro Tercentenary Celebration, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Elena Lucrezia Cornaro Piscopia, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Women's Studies Annual Prize Competition Flyers, 1983-1993 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Elizabeth Segel Lecture, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Maurine Greenwald Lecture, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - "The Women's Suffrage Movement: Words and Deeds" Exhibit, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Mary Elaine Hegland Lecture, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Susan Schaefer Davis Lecture, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Donna Ferrato Lecture, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Women's Studies Programming, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - David Saker Lecture, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - "Women, Gender, and Economic Restructuring" Seminar (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Women's Studies Program Speaker Series, 1997-2002 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Activism, VI.
  This series contains information about participation in activist events by those in the Women's Studies Program. It includes information about several marches and rallies attended by members of the program.
  - March for Women's Lives, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania March for Women's Lives, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - March for Equality/March for Women's Lives, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mobilize for Women's Lives, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - March for Women's Lives, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Conferences, VII.
  This series includes information and fliers about conferences regarding women's studies topics. Records pertain to conferences held by the university and others in the surrounding area, as well as throughout the country.
  - Women's Studies Conferences, 1977-1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 8th Annual North East Regional Conference, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meeting of the Psychological Association, "Team Teaching the Psychology of Women", 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Women Writer's Conference, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Impact of the E.R.A. on the Changing Roles of Men, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Celebration of Women" Conference, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Half-Day Resource Conference, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Conference on Women In the Arts, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Resources for Women Wanting Careers in Engineering and Computers, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Surviving and Thriving in Graduate and Professional School, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Teaching Women's Studies Conference, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Women's History Syposium/ 2nd Annual Tri-State Women's Studies Conference, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Mental Health and Women: Breaking Barriers Conference, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 3rd Annual Women's Studies Conference, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Conference for Women Graduate Students, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 4th Annual Tri-State Women's Studies Conference, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 2nd Annual Mental Health and Women Conference, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Conference for Women Graduate Students, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 5th Annual Tri-State Women's Studies Conference, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Sexism and Racism in Universities", 1989 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 6th Annual Tri-State Women's Studies Conference, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Conference for Women Graduate Students, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - The Obstacle Course: Professional Women Past and Present, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Still the Second Sex: Gender Issues in the 1990s, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 7th Annual Tri-State Women's Studies Conference, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Beyond Borders: Building Bridges, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - 8th Annual Tri-State Women's Studies Conference, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Women Changing Pennsylvania Politics, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Feminism in Faith and Practice, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 9th Annual Tri-State Women's Studies Conference, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Feminist Ethics and Social Policy Conference, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Women In Development Conference, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Women in Development Conference, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Harriet Woods Conference, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Women At Pitt, VIII.
  This series contains information about organizations created by women at the University of Pittsburgh. These include committees and organizations created by the Women's Studies faculty.
  - Campus Women's Organization (CWO), 1986-1995 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Community Contacts Committee (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Consciousness Raising Groups (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Provost Advisory Committee on Women's Concerns, 1991-1996 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Publicity and Programs Committee, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Publicity and Committees, 1977-1988 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Research and Bibliography Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Research and Development Committee, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Women's Information Service and Exchange (WISE), 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 48)
- News Clippings, IX.
  This series includes news clippings regarding the Women's Studies Program and women's issues.
  - Copies of Women's Studies News Articles, 1970-1979 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Copies of Women's Studies News Articles, 1980-1989 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Copies of Women's Studies News Articles, 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Women's Center News Articles, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - News Articles, 1969-1994 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Women's Press and Periodicals, 1984-1988 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Women's Studies Announcements in the University Times, 1985-1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Women's Studies News Articles, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Women's Studies News Articles, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Women's Studies News Articles, 1981-1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Women's Studies News Articles, 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Subject Files, X.
  This series contains information gathered regarding several national organizations of women, as well as articles on women in several areas of society.
  - The Allegheny Feminist, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - American Association of University Women, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Articles on Women, 1986-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Association for Women in Education, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Association for Women in Psychology, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 10)